<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Renata Hirota&#39;s website</title>
<link>https://hirota.dev/projects/</link>
<atom:link href="https://hirota.dev/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.8.27</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Mapping mechanized agriculture in indigenous lands</title>
  <link>https://hirota.dev/projects/commodity-crops-indigenous-lands/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><img src="https://hirota.dev/projects/commodity-crops-indigenous-lands/lavouras.webp" class="preview-image img-fluid"></p>
<p>A study commissioned by news outlet O Joio e o Trigo revealed that the state of Mato Grosso, an agricultural powerhouse, hosts approximately 73,000 hectares of mechanized plantations within its indigenous lands.</p>
<p>The research, conducted by geographer Felipe Sodré and geologist Dr.&nbsp;Natalie Aubet, employed satellite imagery from January 2021 to May 2023, utilizing advanced segmentation techniques for accurate mapping. Of the 72 indigenous territories in the state, 21 were found to contain commodity crops, raising concerns about leases, invasions, and ongoing legal disputes. This unprecedented insight into the intersection of agriculture and indigenous lands underscores the complex dynamics at play in Mato Grosso.</p>
<p>The interactive maps featured in the story were made by me with Leaflet from the original data provided by the researchers.</p>
<p><em>Read more <a href="https://ojoioeotrigo.com.br/2023/07/mato-grosso-tem-lavoura-mecanizada-dentro-de-terras-indigenas/">here</a>.</em></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>agribusiness</category>
  <category>spatial</category>
  <category>o joio e o trigo</category>
  <guid>https://hirota.dev/projects/commodity-crops-indigenous-lands/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Engolindo Fumaça (Inhaling Smoke)</title>
  <link>https://hirota.dev/projects/engolindo-fumaca/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://hirota.dev/projects/engolindo-fumaca/engolindo-fumaca.webp" class="preview-image img-fluid figure-img" alt="SMOKE IN THE TAPAJÓS NATIONAL FOREST, AMAZON REGION OF PARÁ STATE, SEPTEMBER 2020"></p>
<figcaption>Photo: Marizilda Cruppe / Amazônia Real</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Inhaling Smoke is a special project that investigates the effects of air pollution caused by wildfires on the health of the Brazilian Amazon population during the pandemic.</p>
<p>In 2020, the tragic combination of the Covid-19 pandemic and one of the most severe cycles of fires and deforestation in the Brazilian Amazon meant that residents of fire-affected regions were also more exposed to the risk of Covid-19 worsening. Breathing, especially in municipalities in the states of Rondônia, Mato Grosso, Acre and Amazonas, has become more dangerous.</p>
<p>This toxic synergy was the object of an unprecedented data analysis carried out by a multidisciplinary team of journalists, geographers, statisticians from InfoAmazonia, in partnership with researchers from LabGama, from the Federal University of Acre, and Fiocruz’s Climate and Health Observatory/ICICT. The project was supported by Stanford University through the Big Local News program, which aims to open up data in formats that can be replicated by journalists around the world.</p>
<p><em>Learn more about this project <a href="https://infoamazonia.org/en/project/inhaling-smoke/">here</a>.</em></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>health</category>
  <category>environmental</category>
  <category>infoamazonia</category>
  <guid>https://hirota.dev/projects/engolindo-fumaca/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
